<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>[NAME] Announcements on Tile | Forget debugging in the console</title>
    <link>https://underplot.com/dataTile/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in [NAME] Announcements on Tile | Forget debugging in the console</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 20:33:11 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://underplot.com/dataTile/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Debug SwiftUI with a custom view modifier</title>
      <link>https://underplot.com/dataTile/blog/2023-02-27-swiftui-modifier/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://underplot.com/dataTile/blog/2023-02-27-swiftui-modifier/</guid>
      <description>Logging values and seeing them visualized in dataTile is pretty powerful but the core concept of the app really shines when a developer would automate logs that drive metrics over time.
Such metrics could be any value that changes over time — the size of the app cache, consumed RAM, or how many instances of a given class are created.
In this article we&amp;rsquo;ll look into logging how many times a SwiftUI view is re-created.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dataTile for Simulator 1.4</title>
      <link>https://underplot.com/dataTile/blog/2023-02-20-datatile-1.4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://underplot.com/dataTile/blog/2023-02-20-datatile-1.4/</guid>
      <description>dataTile for Simulator 1.4 is a minor update bringing a number of quality-of-life improvements to the app:
When you relaunch your iOS app from Xcode — dataTile for Simulator detects the restart and resets the data in the currently visible tiles so you see only the data since the latest app launch. This improvement relieves the need to add pre-run script to projects — dataTile now detects relaunches and reset the data on its own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dataTile for Simulator launches today!</title>
      <link>https://underplot.com/dataTile/blog/2023-01-03-datatile-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://underplot.com/dataTile/blog/2023-01-03-datatile-launch/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m glad to share that dataTile for Simulator is launching today on ProductHunt and the AppStore today!
dataTile for Simulator is an Xcode companion app to see your debugging data in a beautiful and bold UI. Log your debug data as usual using Apple&amp;rsquo;s logging framework, and dataTile for Simulator will automatically select and display your logs!
It&amp;rsquo;s a powerful native developer tool that is focused on making developers more productive while developing with Xcode and the Simulator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dataTile for Simulator is on TestFlight now!</title>
      <link>https://underplot.com/dataTile/blog/2022-11-28-testflight-beta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 09:43:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://underplot.com/dataTile/blog/2022-11-28-testflight-beta/</guid>
      <description>Today &amp;ldquo;dataTile for Simulator&amp;rdquo; is available as a public beta on TestFlight.
Install the beta version from TestFlight
The open beta will run through the month of December and all beta testers will have access to Pro features:
What&amp;rsquo;s available in the beta? Running safely in the mac app sandbox. Reads logs from the Xcode Simulator in real time. Automatically captures relevant log lines and displays the data. Beautiful data visualization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beta Available Now!</title>
      <link>https://underplot.com/dataTile/blog/2022-11-16-public-beta/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 09:43:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://underplot.com/dataTile/blog/2022-11-16-public-beta/</guid>
      <description>The public beta of dataTile is available today. Download on a mac computer and power up your development with beautiful real-time debug data!
What&amp;rsquo;s available in the beta? Use dataTile as a beautiful log renderer, instead of using prints. Automatically captures relevant log lines and displays the data. Real-time text or chart visualization. Integrate in your Xcode workflow with no code changes. Download the beta version here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reroute print() to the unified log system</title>
      <link>https://underplot.com/dataTile/blog/2022-10-16-pipe-print-to-logs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 09:42:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://underplot.com/dataTile/blog/2022-10-16-pipe-print-to-logs/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re usually using print(...) in Swift to print debug info to the output console, it might be difficult to fight muscle memory and use os_log(...) instead.
Luckily, you can easily create a simple replacement for print() if you want to route some of that sweet, sweet debug info to the app logs and from there see them straight in dataTile!
Additionally, you might have some print statements sprinkled here and there and want to now capture them with dataTile&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
